Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to create a safe system.
With this safe system, we're going to be able to save things such as the amount of life that my character
has.
And we'll also be able to make a level unlock system with it.
So to get started, go to the player blueprint folder.
And Right Click and Go Blueprint class and look for a saved game.
Just select it and call this player save.
Once you've done that, open it up.
We're now going to create the variables that we want to save inside of our game.
So create a variable and call this life's.
And just change this verbal type to be a float.
Then create a new variable and call this coins.
Then create another variable and call it apples, then create one more variable and call this levels
and change this variable type to be a boolean.
And change this to be an array and go compile.
So you may have multiple levels in your game.
So we're making this an array.
That way we can hold and save the data of multiple levels.
Once you've done this, just close this, then go over to the main menu widget.
And because in our game, this main menu is going to be the first thing that our player character sees.
We're going to create our save game here next.
If we go over to the graph after a bank construct where we show our mouse cursor and set our player
controller to input mode UI only, we're going to check to see if we have a saved game.
We can do that by dragging over here and looking for Does save game exist?
First lot name type in one.
That's what we're going to call our save game and drag off the return value and look for Branch.
So we're going to check to see do we have a save game under slot?
Name one.
If we don't, then we're going to create a save game.
So look for create Save Game object.
And under the Save Game class, select what we called our save game.
So I called mine player save.
Then right click on this return body and promote it to a variable and call this RC reference.
But when we create a safe game for the first time, we're going to set the starting variables inside
of our set game.
If we go back to our player, save and select the lives under lives, type in three.
This is the amount of lives that I want my player character to start the game with.
And if I go to my apples, I'm going to make it to.
The player starts with five apples.
And if we go to levels, just go add new element and add three elements.
Just check zero and check one.
I'm going to be ignoring zero for one.
This basically will represent level one and by default we want level one to be unlocked.
So make sure this is checked.
Okay.
So after we create our safe game reference to track up here and for save game to slot and the slot name
type in one.
And this will create a save game under the slot.
Name one with all this data.
If we already have a save game, then we're going to do nothing so we can just leave this blank.
Next, if we compile this and save it, go over to our player blueprint.
Then if we open up our player blueprint and go over to Event Pick n Play event we can play.
We are going to reference all the variables inside of our shape and we'll make it so our player character
has the values from these variables.
So if we drag off event book and play book for load game from slot and put the slot name type in one.
Then drag off this return body and look for cost to play a same.
Just right click and promote this to variable as we'll be referencing this later.
And then from here, I'm just going to select everything and move it back a bit.
We are going to get the amount of lights that we have.
We will get them out apples that we have and we will get them out of coins that we have.
And then for player character, if we drag in their lives and look for set track in their coins and
look for set and track in their apples and look for set.
We can then connect all of these values here.
So if our lives are connected.
Bitcoins are connect here and the apples are connected.
And we can just connect all these notes.
And connect this into here and now.
If I could compile, save and close this, I'm going to go to my main menu level and save everything
if I go play.
It should create a save game for me.
And now if I go start and go to level one, I should start my game with five apples, three lives and
zero coins.
So it looks like my save game is working nice.